Guide to the Humphreys-Marvin-Olmstead Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Humphreys-Marvin-Olmstead collection
1776-1867
MS 857
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3
(8 boxes, 1 folio)
A collection of unrelated papers, linked by the family connections of the major figures. The papers of David Humphreys, a diplomat in the service of the United States, document his activities in Spain, 1789-1808. Also included are personal papers including correspondence with David Bushnell and Ezra Lee about submarines and with James Madison on politics, and some family correspondence. The papers of George William Erving, who was chargé d'affaires in Madrid (1804-1809) during Humphreys' tenure, complement the Humphreys diplomatic papers. The Marvin and Lemuel Gregory Olmstead (also Olmsted) families are represented by correspondence concerning life in New York and Connecticut in the 19th century. Of particular interest is a series of some sixty letters from Sarah Lucy Olmstead to her father describing her life in Erie, Pennsylvania from 1860-1865. Also in this part of the collection is a family photograph album and a journal kept by Lemuel Gregory Olmstead of his travels in New York State during 1830.
Humphreys, David, 1752-1818
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Griswold family and others.
Arrangement
Arranged by name of family member.
Scope and Contents
This collection is composed of fragmented groups of papers pertaining to the interrelated Humphreys, Marvin, and Olmsted families; they date from the Revolutionary War era through the first half of the nineteenth century. The papers fall into five distinct and unrelated series, each devoted to a different family or group of families. For the convenience of the researcher, a detailed genealogical chart has been provided, which identifies all family members represented in the collection.
By far the most important person having a place in this collection is David Humphreys, Revolutionary War officer and United States diplomat, whose papers make up the first and largest series (see the description of Series I). Humphrey's papers, which are concerned for the most part with his diplomatic activities in Spain from 1789 to 1808, are complemented by diplomatic papers of George William Erving, charge d'affaires in Madrid from 1804 to 1809 (Series II). These two sets of papers together thus provide a useful resource for the student of early American diplomacy.
Series III and IV contain correspondence, legal and financial papers, genealogical materials, and memorabilia of the Marvin and Lemuel Gregory Olmsted families. While neither series is very large or coherent, a picture does emerge of everyday life in Connecticut, New York, and Pennsylvania during the early 1800s.
The fifth series is composed of four separate small collections of papers pertaining to Joel Barlow, the Cary and Dwight families, and John Trumbull, and of a collection of miscellaneous autographs (see page 61). Since John Trumbull materials are also located in Series I and II, an index to all the Trumbull materials has been compiled.
The Humphreys-Marvin-Olmsted Collection (Manuscript Group Number 189) by Wolcott Griswold Lane, a descendant of the Griswold and Colt families.
Biographical / Historical
David Humphreys: soldier, statesman, poet; B.A., Yale, 1771, M.A., 1774; lieutenant colonel and aide-de-camp to Washington during the Revolution; appointed special secret agent in 1790 to gather information for Secretary of State Thomas Jefferson; appointed commissioner of Algerian states; in 1793 appointed minister plenipotentiary to Spain; in 1796, upon his return to the U.S., founded the Humphreysville Manufacturing Company.
For a chart outlining the genealogical relations of the Humphreys, Marvin, and Olmstead families, please consult the Genealogical Chart.
Other Finding Aids
For an index of authors and the boxes in which their materials are located, please consult the Author Index.
Armed Forces; Families; Music; Science; Submarines (Ships); Connecticut -- Social life and customs; Erie (Pa.) -- Social life and customs; New England -- Description and travel; New York (State) -- Description and travel; New York (State) -- Social life and customs; Spain -- Foreign relations -- United States; United States -- Description and travel; United States -- Foreign relations -- Spain; United States -- History -- Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775; United States -- History -- War of 1812; United States -- Politics and government; Autobiographies; Diaries; Diplomats; New England -- Description and travel -- Early works to 1800; Adams, John, 1735-1826; Barlow, Joel, 1754-1812; Barlow, Samuel L. M. (Samuel Latham Mitchill), 1826-1889; Beecher, Henry Ward, 1813-1887; Burr, Aaron, 1756-1836; Bushnell, David, 1740-; Cary, Christopher, 1763-1837; Clay, Henry, 1777-1852; Clinton, DeWitt, 1769-1828; Colt, Judah, 1761-1832; Deane, Silas, 1737-1789; Dwight, Timothy, 1726-1777; Dwight, Timothy, 1752-1817; Dwight, Timothy, 1811-1842; Dwight, William T. (William Theodore), 1795-1865; Erving, George William, 1769-1850; Howe, Joseph, 1746/7-1775; Humphreys, David, 1752-1818; King, Rufus, 1755-1827; Marvin, Elizabeth, 1767-1834; Morris, Gouverneur, 1752-1816; Morse, Jedidiah, 1761-1826; Olmstead, Aaron Barlow, b. 1812; Olmstead, Almira, b. 1807; Olmstead, Lemuel Gregory, 1808-1880; Olmstead, Sarah Lucy, 1840-1871; Pickering, Timothy, 1745-1829; Randolph, Edmund, 1753-1813; Ryan, Samuel; Smith, William Loughton, 1758-1812; Trumbull, John, 1750-1831; Trumbull, Jonathan, 1710-1785; Washington, George, 1732-1799; Webster, Noah, 1758-1843; Dwight family; Ely family; Humphrey family; Marvin family; Olmstead family; Yale University -- History
- DAVID HUMPHREYS PAPERS, (1783-1818)-[ca. 1835]; Series I; 1.5' (4 boxes, 1 folio)
  Scope and Contents
  This series, which is divided into seven sections, is devoted to papers of the diplomat David Humphreys (1752-1818). The bulk of the papers (1789-1808) deals with Humphreys' labors in Europe as an agent of the United States government, both as commissioner for Algerian affairs empowered to negotiate peace with Algiers and arrange ransom for American prisoners, and as minister plenipotentiary to Spain charged with maintaining peaceful relations with Spain and her American colonies.
  The first section, Diplomatic Correspondence, is made up of five sub-sections. The first contains letters written to Humphreys by successive secretaries of state, supplemented by a letterbook in the fifth sub-section (Box 4, folder 111) of letters from Secretary of State Edmund Randolph. These letters provide detailed instructions for Humphreys' missions to Europe, discuss the finances of the missions, and report on political developments in the U.S. The second sub-section contains Humphreys' responses to the secretary of state, in which he describes his activities and those of the foreign governments with which he was dealing, and discusses events through-out Europe. Several of these letters are personal communications to Timothy Pickering; the remainder consists of file copies of some 250 official despatches written by Humphreys in his capacity as minister plenipotentiary. There is, in addition, a letterbook (Box 4, folder 110) entitled "Report of Proceedings of D. Humphreys, Relative to the secret and public transactions and Negotiations In which he was concerned from the 26th day of July 1790," which contains copies of despatches 1-54, as well as a description of Humphreys' original assignment from George Washington in 1790, his plans and preliminary activities before arriving in Europe, and copies of correspondence and secret instructions from the secretary of state.
  The third sub-section of Diplomatic Correspondence consists of correspondence with persons other than the secretary of state. Arranged alphabetically, it contains for the most part letters of diplomats and government officials. Its largest component is correspondence exchanged between Humphreys and William L. Smith, minister plenipotentiary to Portugal from 1797 to 1801, in which events in Portugal are discussed. A somewhat smaller set of letters to Joel Barlow from Humphreys reports on diplomatic developments in Spain. The fourth sub-section contains electrostatic copies of all enclosures to letters in Section 1, arranged alphabetically by author; the fifth contains the two letterbooks described above. Section 2, Diplomatic Miscellany, is made up of newspaper clippings, writings, copies of petitions and other documents, and similar materials, all pertaining to Humphreys' diplomatic career. The papers are arranged chronologically.
  The five remaining sections of Series I are composed of personal papers of David Humphreys. Section 3, General Correspondence, contains a small number of letters exchanged with family members, friends, and acquaintences. It is arranged alphabetically. Among the noteworthy items in this section are correspondence with David Bushnell and Ezra Lee about submarines, a letter from James Madison condemning alliance with France and trade restrictions in 1813, a letter to Humphreys' brother John describing his arrival in Lisbon, and a letter to Martha Washington on the death of her husband.
  Section 4, Third-Party Correspondence, contains several items of correspondence of people other than David Humphreys, again arranged alphabetically. Of particular interest are memoranda by David Bushnell about his submarine and a letter from Benjamin Silliman describing David Humphreys' funeral.
  Section 5, Literary Miscellany, is made up of drafts and notes for writings by Humphreys, and manuscript copies of letters by George Washington, all arranged chronologically, as are the contents of Section 6, Commissions, Diplomas, Certificates. The final section, Genealogy, Biography, and Engravings, is arranged by type of material.
  Folders with asterisks (*) contain ten or more items.
  - Diplomatic Correspondence
    - Incoming from Secretary of State
      - 1794 Jan 20-Dec 31, From Edmund Randolph (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - 1795 Feb 11-Nov 23, From Edmund Randolph (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - 1796 Jan 23-Jun 21, From Timothy Pickering (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 1796 Nov 11-Dec 9, From Timothy Pickering (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - 1797 Feb 1-May 5, From Timothy Pickering (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - 1797 Jul 15-Oct 31, From Timothy Pickering (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - 1797 Dec 2, From Timothy Pickering (Box 1, Folder 7)
        General
        Enclosing: (1) Casa Yrujo, Carlos Martinez de Yrujo y Tacon, Marques de, A Letter to Timothy Pickering, Esq.… from the Chevalier de Yrujo… Dated July 11, 1797. [Philadelphia? 1797]. 15 pp. (2) U.S. 5th Congress. 2nd session, 1797. House. Speech of the President of the United States… November 23, 1797. [See Annals of Congress, 5th Congress, 1797-1799, Vol. 1, col. 630.] (3) U.S. 5th Congress. 2nd Session, 1797. House. An Address in Answer to the Speech of the President… to Both Houses of Congress… (4) Newspaper Clipping of Answer of the U.S. Senate to Speech of President of U.S., Dated Nov. 28, 1797. [See Annals of Congress, 5th Congress, 1797-1799, Vol. 1, col. 472.]
      - 1797 Dec 5-Dec 28, From Timothy Pickering (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - 1798 Mar 3-Apr 19, From Timothy Pickering (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - 1798 Jun 2-Nov 30, From Timothy Pickering (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - 1799 Feb 11-Dec 20, From Timothy Pickering (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - 1800 Apr 29, May 7, From Timothy Pickering (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - 1800 May 14, From Charles Lee, ad interim (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - 1800 Aug 2, From John Marshall (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - 1801 Mar 17; Mar [], From Levi Lincoln, ad interim (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - 1801 May 21 (two versions), Jun 22, From James Madison (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Outgoing to Secretary of State
      - 1796 Jan 23, [To Timothy Pickering], No. 2, Electrostatic copy of MS extract enclosed in D. Humphreys to Joel Barlow, 1796 Apr 27, Box 2, folder 38. (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - 1796 Mar 14, [To Timothy Pickering], No. 4, Electrostatic copy of MS extract enclosed in D. Humphreys to Joel Barlow, 1796 Apr 27, Box 2, folder 38. (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - 1796 Apr 25, [To Timothy Pickering], No. 1, Electrostatic copy of MS copy enclosed in D. Humphreys to Joel Barlow, 1796 Apr 27, Box 2, folder 38. (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - 1797 Apr 20-Aug 15, [To Timothy Pickering], Private Correspondence, File Copies (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - 1798 Jan 9-Sep 28, [To Timothy Pickering], Despatch Nos. 126, 160-164, File Copies (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - 1798 Oct 1-Dec 28, [To Timothy Pickering], Despatch Nos. 165-178, File Copies(*) (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - 1799 Jan 4-Mar 29, [To Timothy Pickering], Despatch Nos. 179-190, File Copies(*) (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - 1799 Apr 2-May 28, [To Timothy Pickering], Despatch Nos. 191-202, File Copies(*) (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - 1799 Jun 4-Jul 26, [To Timothy Pickering], Despatch Nos. 203-212., File Copies (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - 1799 Aug 2-Sep 24, [To Timothy Pickering], Despatch Nos. 213-220, File Copies (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - 1799 Oct 4-Dec 27, [To Timothy Pickering], Despatch Nos. 221-228, File Copies (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - 1800 Jan 3-May 9, [To Timothy Pickering], Despatch Nos. 229-239, File Copies(*) (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - 1800 May 20, 29, [To Charles Lee, ad interim], Despatch Nos. 240-241, File Copies (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - 1800 Jun 13-Aug 22, [To John Marshall], Despatch Nos. 242-247, File Copies (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - 1800 Sep 2-Dec 19, [To John Marshall], Despatch Nos. 248-260, File Copies(*) (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - 1801 Jan 13-Mar 2, [To John Marshall], Despatch Nos. 261-264, File Copies (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - 1801 Mar 6-Apr 28, [To Levi Lincoln, ad interim], Despatch Nos. 265-274, File Copies(*) (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - 1801 May 5-Jul 31, [To James Madison], Despatch Nos. 275-283, File Copies (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - 1801 Aug 21-Oct 20, [To James Madison], Despatch Nos. 284-291, File Copies (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - 1801 Nov 6-Dec 28, [To James Madison], Despatch Nos. 292-299, File Copies (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Other Correspondence
      - Barlow, Joel, 1754-1812
        - 6 ALS and ADS, with enclosures, from D. Humphreys (recipient's copies), 1795 September 7, September 21, October 3, October 4, October 5, October 7 (Box 2, Folder 37)
        - 6 ALS, with enclosures, from D. Humphreys (recipient's copies), 1796 February 1, February 16, February 17, February 20, March 18, April 27 (Box 2, Folder 38)
        - 6 ALS, with enclosures, from D. Humphreys (recipient's copies), 1796 May 6, May 30 (2 letter), June 18, June 19, July 23 (Box 2, Folder 39)
        - Letters from D. Humphreys (3 versions: recipient's copy, file copy, transcript), 1796 July 26 (Box 2, Folder 39)
        - 3 LS, with enclosures, from D. Humphreys (recipient's copies), 1796 August 3 (2 versions) August 5 (Box 2, Folder 40)
        - 5 ALS, with enclosures, from D. Humphreys (recipient's copies), 1796 August 5 October 8, October 18, (2 letter) November 4 (Box 2, Folder 40)
        - 5 ALS, with enclosures, from D. Humphreys (recipient's copies), 1797 February 21, February 28, March 14, April 22, 1798 March 19 (Box 2, Folder 41)
        - Copy of letter from D. Humphreys, 1797 November 28 (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - Cevallos, Pedro
        - 2 letters to D. Humphreys (copies), 1802 February 3, February 4 (Box 2, Folder 42)
        - Copy of letter from D. Humphreys, 1802 February 1 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      - Donaldson, Joseph, Jr.
        - 4 ALS and ADS, with enclosures, from D. Humphreys (file copies), 1795 May 18, May 21, May 23, July 23 (Box 2, Folder 43)
      - Hassan Pasha, Dey of Algiers, reigned 1791-1798
        - 4 ALS and ADS, with enclosures, from D. Humphreys (file copies), 1796 August 3, (2 versions), November 4, November 5 (Box 2, Folder 44)
      - Joyes (Messrs. Patrick) & Sons
        - File copy of letter from D. Humphreys, 1801 August 2 (Box 2, Folder 44)
      - King, Rufuss, 1755-1827
        - Copy of letter, with enclosure, to D. Humphreys, 1798 February 19 (Box 2, Folder 46)
        - ALS to D. Humphreys, 1798 May 20 (Box 2, Folder 46)
        - 2 ALS from D. Humphreys, 1798 May 22, June 1 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - [Lear, Tobias, 1762-1816?]
        - AL to D. Humphreys, 1791 October 19 (Box 2, Folder 47)
        - ALS to D. Humphreys, 1792 June 24 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - Montgomery, Robert, U.S. Consul at Alicante
        - ALS to D. Humphreys, 1794 December 6 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - Morris, Gouverneur, 1752-1816
        - 2 LS to D. Humphreys, 1792 December 6 1793 June 5 (Box 2, Folder 49)
        - 2 letters from D. Humphreys (file copies), 1792 August 14 1793 January 28 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - O'Brien [O'Bryen], Richard
        - Petition of O'Brien, et al, to D. Humphreys, 1793 December 29 (Box 2, Folder 50)
        - Electrostatic copy of AL from D. Humphreys. Original MS enclosed in D. Humphreys to Joel Barlow, 1796 Aug 3, Box 2, folder 40, 1796 August 3 (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - Pickering, Timothy, 1745-1829
        - Letter to D. Humphreys (2 versions: ALS; LS with en-closure entitled: "Memoranda of points to be noticed in answering Col. Humphreys' Letters."), 1800 May 28 (Box 2, Folder 51)
      - Pinckney, Charles Cotesworth, 1746-1825
        - 2 ALS, with enclosure, to D. Humphreys, 1798 June 1, 1808 December 5 (Box 2, Folder 52)
      - Pinckney, Thomas, 1750-1828
        - 2 ALS, with enclosure, to D. Humphreys, 1792 December 24, 1794 October 28 (Box 2, Folder 53)
      - Pinto, [de Souza, Luis]
        - AL to D. Humphreys, 1790 November 23 (Box 2, Folder 54)
      - Remsen, Henry, Jr.
        - ALS to D. Humphreys, 1791 September 17 (Box 2, Folder 55)
      - St. Vincent, John Jervis, Earl of, 1735-1823
        - LS to D. Humphreys, 1797 August 14 (Box 2, Folder 56)
      - Simpson, James, Russian Consul at Gibraltar
        - ALS to D. Humphreys (2 versions: recipient's copy, duplicate copy), 1795 January 3 (Box 2, Folder 57)
        - 2 ALS to D. Humphreys, 1795 January 5, December 19 (Box 2, Folder 57)
      - Smith, William [Loughton], 1758-1812
        - 2 ALS to D. Humphreys, 1797 August 22, December 15 (Box 2, Folder 58)
        - 9 ALS, with enclosures, to D. Humphreys(*), 1798 January 17-September 18 (Box 2, Folder 59)
        - 6 letters from D. Humphreys (file copies), 1798 April 13-September 28 (Box 2, Folder 59)
        - 6 ALS, with enclosures, to D. Humphreys, 1798 October 19, November 3, November 17, December 18, December 21, December 29 (Box 2, Folder 60)
        - 3 letters from D. Humphreys (file copies), 1798 October 23, October 30, December 28 (Box 2, Folder 60)
        - 6 ALS, with enclosures, to D. Humphreys(*), 1799 January 3-March 20 (Box 2, Folder 61)
        - 6 letters from D. Humphreys (file copies), 1799 January 4-March 12 (Box 2, Folder 61)
        - 10 ALS to D. Humphreys(*), 1799 April 6-August 24 (Box 2, Folder 62)
        - 2 letters from D. Humphreys (file copies), 1799 March 22-June 14 (Box 2, Folder 62)
        - 10 ALS to D. Humphreys(*), 1799 September 3-December 31 (Box 2, Folder 63)
        - 3 letters from D. Humphreys (file copies), 1799 October 11-October 25 (Box 2, Folder 63)
        - 19 ALS, with enclosures, to D. Humphreys(*), 1800 February 28-December 27 (Box 2, Folder 64)
        - 12 ALS to D. Humphreys(*), 1801 February 21-October 3 (Box 2, Folder 65)
      - Valliere,_______;, French Consul-General at Algiers
        - ALS to D. Humphreys, 1794 December 28 (Box 2, Folder 66)
      - [Venegas?] de Saavendra, Francesco [Xavier?], 1754-1838
        - ALS to D. Humphreys, 1798 June 16 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Enclosures
      - Adams, John, 1735-1826
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to Charles IV, King of Spain, 1788-1808. Original MS copy enclosed in John Marshall to D. Humphreys, 1800 Aug 2, Box 1, folder 14, 1800 January 18 (Box 3, Folder 68)
        - Amory, [Samuel?]
          See: box 3, folder 79
        - Baccri, Micaiah
          See: box 3, folder 72
      - Casa Calvo,_______;, Marques de
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to William Empson Hulings. Original MS copy enclosed in Timothy Pickering to D. Humphreys, 1799 Dec 20, Box 1, folder 11, 1799 October 4 (Box 3, Folder 69)
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to Evan Jones. Original MS copy enclosed in Timothy Pickering to D. Humphreys, 1799 Dec 20, Box 1, folder 11, 1799 October 4 (Box 3, Folder 70)
      - [Casa Yrujo,] Carlos Martinez de Yrujo [y Tacon, Marques de], 1763-1824
        - Electrostatic copies of 3 letters to Timothy Pickering. Original MS copies and English translations enclosed, respectively, in Timothy Pickering to D. Humphreys, 1797 Oct 31, Box 1, folder 6; 1797 Dec 7, Box 1, folder 8; 1798 Jun 2, Box 1, folder 10, 1797 June 15, November 21, 1798 April 24[?] (Box 3, Folder 71)
      - Cathalan, Stephen, Jr.
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to M_______; Delamotte [La Motte, Lamotte], enclosing an extract of a letter from [Micaiah?] Baccri to [Solomon?] Baccri dated 1795 Sep 16. Original MS copy enclosed in D. Humphreys to Joel Barlow, 1795 Oct 4, Box 2, folder 37, 1795 September 24 (Box 3, Folder 72)
        - Electrostatic copy of extracts of 3 letters to [James Monroe, 1758-1831?] Original MS copy enclosed in Timothy Pickering to D. Humphreys, 1796 Jan 23, Box 1, folder 3, 1795 September 24, September 25, September 26 (Box 3, Folder 73)
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to Robert Montgomery. Original MS copy[?] enclosed in Timothy Pickering to D. Humphreys, 1798 Apr 14, Box 1, folder 9, 1798 January 29 (Box 3, Folder 74)
      - Chiappe, Franco [Francisco, Francesco]
        - Electrostatic copies of 2 letters to George Washington. Original MSS enclosed in Edmund Randolph to D. Humphreys, 1794 Dec 31, Box 1, folder 1, 1793 March 20, 1794 March 20[?] (Box 3, Folder 75)
      - Culnan, John
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to Timothy Pickering, enclosing a copy of letter to same, dated 1799 Oct 25. Original MS copies enclosed in Timothy Pickering to D. Humphreys, 1800 Apr 29, Box 1, folder 12, 1799 November 4 (Box 3, Folder 76)
      - Gonzales [Gonzalez], Don Blas
        - Electrostatic copies of 2 versions of letter to George Washington. Original MS copies in English translation enclosed in Timothy Pickering to D. Humphreys, 1796 Nov 11, Box 1, folder 4, 1795 December 12 (Box 3, Folder 77)
      - Hawley, Daniel
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to Timothy Pickering. Original MS copy enclosed in Timothy Pickering to D. Humphreys, 1798 Apr 10, Box 1, folder 9, [1798 Mar?] (Box 3, Folder 78)
      - Head and Amory (Messrs) & Co.
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to Timothy Pickering. Original MS copy enclosed in Timothy Pickering to D. Humphreys, 1798 Apr 14, Box 1, folder 9, 1798 March 6 (Box 3, Folder 79)
      - Jaudenes, Josef de
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to Edmund Randolph. Original MS copy enclosed in Edmund Randolph to D. Humphreys, 1795 Apr 12, Box 1, folder 2, 1795 April 7 (Box 3, Folder 80)
      - [Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826]
        - Electrostatic copy of extract of letter to William Carmichael. Original MS extract enclosed in Timothy Pickering to D. Humphreys, 1796 Nov 11, Box 1, folder 4, 1790 April 11 (Box 3, Folder 81)
      - Jones, Evan
        - Electrostatic copy of letter to Marques de Casa Calvo. Original MS copy enclosed in Timothy Pickering to D. Humphreys, 1799 Dec 20, Box 1, folder 11, 1799 September 24 (Box 3, Folder 82)
      - King, Rufus, 1755-1827
        - Electrostatic copies of extracts of 2 letters to [William Loughton Smith]. Original MS extracts enclosed in William L. Smith to D. Humphreys, 1798 Dec 21, Box 2, folder 60, [1798?] February 5, March 9 (Box 3, Folder 83)